justia.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy :: Justia

Justia is committed to protecting the privacy and security of all individuals who use our site. Our goal is to provide an Internet experience that delivers the information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you. In order to achieve this goal, we collect information during your visits. This Privacy Policy is designed to help you learn more about the personal information we collect, who we might share it with, and how we protect it.

_Note: Additional terms and conditions, if any, regarding the collection and use of your information may also be provided to you before you sign up for a particular Justia service - privacy policies for those services will be linked from those particular areas or sections of our site._

## What Information Do We Collect?

Justia collects personal information in three ways - through information provided directly from our users, from information collected through web server logs and through cookies.

**Information Supplied by Our Users**

Justia collects personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address and telephone number. Justia may also collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, and legal interests. Justia does not collect any of this unique information about you except when you specifically and knowingly provide such information.

Justia may retain this information indefinitely, or to the extent permissible by law.

**Information from Web Server Logs**

Justia records and saves information about you from our web server logs such as your Internet [Protocol] (IP) address, the time and day you visited and your browser type. This information is used to verify our records and to provide better services to you.

Justia may retain this information indefinitely, or to the extent permissible by law.

**Information from Cookies**

In order to offer and provide you with personalized services, Justia uses "cookies" to store and help track information about you. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. Justia will not disclose its cookies to third parties except as required by a valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order.

_Note: Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies. You should be aware though that some parts of the Justia Web sites and services may not function properly if you refuse cookies._

## Removal of Information

Justia provides access to some public litigation records from federal and state courts as a public service. These records, some of which are the law of the land, should be available to all to read.

Unless compelled by a valid court order, Justia will not fully remove records that are not under seal. However, we will consider written requests to disallow search engines from processing or scanning certain case filings and opinions using the robots.txt protocol. This means when a person searches for your docket or opinion using a search engine such as Google, that page from Justia should not show up in the search results. Justia has no control over those same documents available from other sources, such as court websites and third-party services. Read more about [our policy](https://dockets.justia.com/why-is-my-information-online) regarding application of the robots.txt protocol.

## Links to Other Sites

Justia encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to visit from Justia so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Justia is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Justia site.

## Use or Disclosure of Your Personal Information to Third Parties and Co-Brand Partners

Justia will not willfully disclose any personal information affirmatively supplied by you, as described above, to any third party without first receiving your permission. Justia may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Justia, protect and defend the rights or property of Justia or act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Justia or members of the public.

Certain Justia services and content may be co-branded with another company. If you register for or use such services, both Justia and the other company may receive information collected in conjunction with the co-branded services. In such cases, either a joint privacy statement or a link to the other company's privacy statement will be provided, which will provide you with information about how the other company will use the information and how you can contact the other company with requests to access the information or other inquiries.

The Justia Lawyer Directory will be sharing all user information with Cornell's Legal Information Institute for their version of the lawyer directory. We may also co-brand the lawyer directory with other third parties, but will not share information marked private or non-public email addresses with those other third parties.

## Advertising Campaigns on Third-Party Websites

Justia advertises on third-party websites to reach people who have previously visited our website. We contract with third-party vendors, including Facebook and Google, to implement this type of advertising campaign, known as remarketing. Based on information collected in cookies, web beacons or other storage technologies from your prior visits to Justia, our advertising vendors will serve ads promoting Justia services to you as you visit their websites or other sites across the Internet, as well as provide us with measurement services on the effectiveness of our ads.

You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting [Google's Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

You can opt out of Facebook’s use of cookies and web beacons by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Consumer Choice Tool for Web](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) and [Your Online Choices: A Guide to Online Behavioral Advertising](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

## Content Submitted Or Made Available For Inclusion On The Service

With respect to content you submit or make available for inclusion on publicly accessible areas of the Service, this information will be made public on the internet. "Publicly accessible" areas of the Service are those areas of the Justia network of properties that are intended by Justia to be available to the general public. By way of example, publicly accessible areas of the Service would include the Justia Lawyer Directory, Justia Ask a Lawyer, wikis, message boards and Justia-developed websites and blogs.

## Protecting Your Information

While Justia is committed to protecting your personal information, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords you set up and/or any account information.

## Correcting Inaccuracies

When you sign up for Justia's products and service, we may send you an email confirming your new account. The message will be sent to the address that you supplied to us at the time of sign-up and will describe ways for you to change or delete the account information provided. Remember to keep the confirmation email as it will also contain information that will help you in case you run into problems accessing our services.

We welcome your comments or questions. Send us an email at justiaprivacypolicy (at) justia.com.

_Last updated April 2018_
